Guide to the Charles Wilkes Papers, 1816-1876 RL.01383
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Bridgers family 1866 Dec. 6; 1867 Mar. 4; 1867 Sept. 9; 1867 Dec. 22; 1870 Apr. 20; 1870 July 25; 1871 Feb. 15; 1871 July 11; 1871 Aug. 9; 1872 Mar. 1; 1872 July 12; 1873 Mar.6; 1873 Aug. 4; 1873 Aug. 27; 1873 Oct. 5; 1873 Nov. 10; 1874 [?].
Bridges, France 1831 Jan. 11
Brinsmade, Peter A. 1835 June 1; Letter to: 1841 Oct. 12.
Bristow, Benjamin Helm 1876 Mar. 26
Brown, Bedford 1860 Nov. 23
Buchanan, Franklin [?] 1848 Jan. 27; 1850 Mar. 4.
Buchanan, James 1847 Dec. 21; 1856 July 24; 1856 Dec. 21; 1857 Mar. 20; 1859 Oct. 21; 1860 May 28; 1861 Jan. 2.
Buchanan, Robert Christie 1863 Feb. 11; 1863 Mar. 5; 1863 Mar. 7; 1863 Mar. 14; 1863 Mar. 15; 1863 Mar. 27.
Burke, Edmund (1809-1882) 1849 Apr. 17; 1849 Apr. 28; 1849 May 6.
Burke, Edmund (1809-1882) [?], 1845[?] Feb. 5
Burnside, Ambrose Everett 1862 Dec. 4; 1863 Feb. 18; 1863 Mar. 7; 1863 Mar. 16.
Butler, Benjamin Franklin (1795-1858) [?] 1849 Mar. 18 [?]
Butler, Benjamin Franklin (1795-1858), 1871 Feb. 7
Caldwell, Greene Washington, 1849 Mar. 22; 1849 Nov. 26; 1850 Jan. 8; 1850 Jan. 14; 1850 Feb. 3; 1853 Apr. 8; 1853 Apr. 16; 1853 Apr. 30; 1855 Dec. 15; 1859[?] Jan. 2.
Calhoun, Floride Bonneau (Colhoun), 1825[?] Mar. 25
Calhoun, John Caldwell 1825 Mar. 25; 1849 May 15; 1850 May 7.
California, 1849 Mar. 12
California. Agriculture 1849 Mar. 2
California. Gold 1849[?] Feb.
California. Gold Mines and Mining, 1849 Mar. 2; 1849 Mar. 31.
California. Gold Rush 1848 Dec. 12; 1849 Jan. 24; 1849 Jan. 29; 1849 Feb. 1; 1849 Feb. 4; 1849 Mar. 2; 1849 Mar. 31.
Camp Sabine. Louisiana 1836 May 5
Candles 1830 Aug. 23
Capps Mining Company 1855 Apr. 19; 1855 July 15; 1855 July 21; 1856 Jan. 19; 1856 Feb. 24; 1856 Mar. 4; 1856 Mar. 31; 1856 June 20; 1856 July 16; 1857 Apr. 30; 1857 May 17.
Carriages and Carts 1825[?] Apr. 9
Carriages and Carts. Italy. Naples 1830 Oct. 25
Cass, Lewis 1846 Apr. 2
Casserly, Eugene 1870 Dec. 9
Cassin, John 1857 Jan. 14; 1857 Jan. 16; 1857 Jan. 27; 1857 Jan. 31; 1857 Feb. 3; 1857 Apr. 4; 1857 Apr. 16; 1857 June 13; 1857 June 16; 1857 June 20; 1857 July 10; 1857 July 17; 1857 Oct. 17; 1857 Dec. 26.
Cassin, John [?] 1852 Nov. 19; 1852 Nov. 22; 1852 Nov. 27.
Catholic Church. Italy. Florence. Chapel of the Medici 1830 Nov. 9
Catholic Church. Italy. Naples. Church of Saint Francis 1830 Oct. 25
Catholic Church. Italy. Naples. Saint Martino Church 1830 Oct. 25
Catholic Church. New York. New York, Writings: "Churches" p. 2
Cattell, Alexander Gilmore 1870 July 5; 1870 Sept. 16; 1870 Dec. 9.
Cemeteries. New York. New York. Greenwood Cemetery Writings: "Greenwood Cemetery"
Cemeteries. Tunis 1830 Sept. 12
Central Ohio Railroad Company, 1852 Apr.-1853 Oct. (scattered); [Letters of Edmund Wilkes] 1854 July 5; 1855 Jan. 13; 1855 Aug. 14; 1855 Oct. 3; 1855 Oct. 11; 1855 Nov. 25; 1855 Dec. 23; 1856 Feb. 9; 1856 Feb. 18; 1856 Apr. 20; 1856 Apr. [?]; 1856 May 10; 1856 Aug. 2; 1856 Aug. 26; 185
Chandler, Joseph Ripley 1854 Dec. 20
Chanler, John Winthrop 1863 Jan. 28; 1863 Feb. 6.
Chase, Salmon Portland 1863 May 22; 1870 May 20.
Chatham Railroad 1865 May 28
Chauncey, Isaac Letter to: 1837 May 25; 1838 Jan. 8.
Chemistry. Study and Teaching Volume: Notebook 1847
Cheney, Benjamin Pierce [?], 1859 Oct. 21
Childbirth 1855 July 12
Chile. Arica. Description and Travel, 1822 Aug. 14
Chile. Army 1826 Feb. 4
Chile. Balls (Parties) 1839 June 12
Chile. Chiloe. History 1826 Feb. 4
Chile. Commerce 1825 Nov. 25; 1826 Feb. 4.
Chile. Police 1839 June 12
Chile. Population 1826 Feb. 4
Chile. Quillota. Description and Travel 1823 Jan. [?]
Chile. Ships 1825 Dec. 14
Chile. Valparaiso. Description and Travel 1822 Feb. 13; 1822 Feb. 20.
Chile. Valparaiso. Earthquakes, 1823 Jan. [?]
Chile. Valparaiso. Social Life and Customs 1822 Feb. 13; 1822 Feb. 20; 1822 Mar. 20; 1822 Mar. 23.
Chile. Wheat 1826 Feb. 4
China. Canton. Description and Travel, 1850 June 23
China. Canton. Fires 1851 Oct. 9[?]
China. Civil Service 1850 Dec. 29
China. Commerce 1850 Oct. 24 (attached to letter of Oct. 2)
China. Crime and Criminals 1850 Oct. 2
China. Description and Travel, 1850 Dec. 3
China. Foreign Population 1850 Sept. 14
China. Foreign Relations. Great Britain 1850 June 23
China. Foreign Relations. Portugal, 1850 June 23
China. Gardens 1850 Dec. 29
China. History. Taiping Rebellion, 1850-1864 1850 Sept. 2; 1850 Sept. 14; 1851 Dec. 8.
China. Junks 1850 June 23
China. Merchant Seamen. Missions and Charities 1850 June 23
China. Merchants 1850 Dec. 3; 1850 Dec. 29.
China. Missionaries 1850 June 23
China. Politics and Government, 1851 Oct. 9 [?]
China. Population 1852 Jan. 3 (with letter of 1851 Dec. 27)
China. Shanghai. Harbors 1850 Dec. 3
China. Manufacture and Refining. Sugar, 1851 Nov. 17
China. Whampoa. Description and Travel, 1850 June 23; 1851 Dec. 27.
China. Whampoa. Population 1850 June 23
China. Whampoa River. Description and Travel 1851 Dec. 27
Choate, Rufus 1843 Dec. 22; 1845[?] Jan. 31.
Chrononlogy. Egyptian 1852 Feb. 13
Civil War. Armies See Confederate States of America. Army; See United States. Army.
Civil War. Blockade Running 1862 Oct. 27
Civil War. Campaigns and Battles. Chambersburg, PA 1862 Oct. 9-12 1862 Oct. 23 (part of letter of Oct. 22)
Civil War. Campaigns and Battles. Chancellorsville, VA 1863 May 1863 May 6; 1863 May 20.
Civil War. Campaigns and Battles. Fort Sumter, SC Clipping: Undated (attached to letter of 1862 Dec. 14; 1863 Apr. 1; 1863 Apr. 2; 1863 Apr. 3; 1863 Apr. 14.
Civil War. Campaigns and Battles. Fredericksburg, VA 1862 Dec. 3; 1863 Jan. 4.
Civil War. Campaigns and Battles. Murfreesboro, TN 1863 Jan. 4
Civil War. Campaigns and Battles. Port Hudson, LA 1863 1863 Apr. 4
Civil War. Campaigns and Battles. Rappahannock Station, VA 1863 Printed Material: 1864 Sept. 20
Civil War. Campaigns and Battles. Suffolk, VA 1863 Printed Material: 1864 Sept. 20
Civil War. Campaigns and Battles. Vicksburg, MS 1863 1863 Apr. 3
Civil War. Contrabands 1862 Aug. 5
Civil War. District of Columbia. Washington 1862 Oct. 23 (part of letter of Oct. 22); 1863 May 5.
Civil War. Fortifications Miscellany: 1862 Aug. 1; Miscellany: 1862 Aug. 25.
Civil War. Maryland. Baltimore 1863 Apr. 1
Civil War. Navies See Confederate States of America. Navy; See United States. Navy.
Civil War. North Carolina. Gaston 1866 Mar. 28
Civil War. Pennsylvania. Philadelphia, 1863 June 17
Civil War. Prisoners. Confederate 1863 May 5; 1863 May 6; 1863 May 19; 1863 June [?].
Civil War. South Carolina. Charleston, 1862 Oct. 23 (part of letter of Oct. 22); Clipping: Undated (attached to letter of 1862 Dec. 14).
Civil War. Unionists in South and Border Areas 1861 Jan. 2; 1861 May 4.
Civil War. Virginia. Petersburg Miscellany: 1862 Aug. 25
Civil War. Virginia. Richmond Miscellany: 1862 Aug. 1
Civil War. Women 1862 Sept. 24; 1862 Oct. 22; 1863 Mar. 15; 1863 Apr. 1.
Clay, Henry Letter to: 1842 Mar. 5; 1845 Dec. 12.
Clayton, John Middleton 1850 July 12
Clayton, John Middleton [?], 1851 [?]
Clergy. British 1830 Dec. 21; 1830 Dec. 25.
Clergy. North Carolina 1866 June 21
Clingman, Thomas Lanier 1858 Feb. 7; 1860 Nov. 23.
Clinton (Iron Manufacturing) Company, 1836 Aug. 6
Clipper Ships 1851 Dec. 8
Clitz, John M.B. 1863 Jan. 27 (letter enclosed with letter of Jan. 28); 1863 Jan. 28 (2); Feb. 4.
Clothing and Dress. France. Paris 1836 Nov. 7
Clothing and Dress. Macao 1851 April 19 (with letter of Mar. 31)
Clothing and Dress. Peru 1823 Jan. [?]
Clothing and Dress. Tunis 1830[?] Sept. 3
Clothing and Dress. Women 1830 Nov. 11; 1831 Jan. 13; 1851 Sept. 18.
Coal. Borneo 1851 Mar. 31
Coal. Formosa 1851 Mar. 31
Coal. Pennsylvania Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XIII)
Coal Company of Deep River 1860 Sept. 3
Coal Mines and Mining. Ohio 1856 Nov. 19
Coal Mines and Mining. Pennsylvania, 1846 Jan. 14
Coal River 1853 Oct. 17
Coal Trade 1846 Aug. 6
Coastal Surveys. Central America 1848 Feb. 4; 1848 Feb. 21.
Coastal Surveys. Mexico 1848 Jan. 19; 1848 Feb. 4.
Coastal Surveys. South America 1848 Feb. 4; 1848 Feb. 21.
Cochrane, Thomas, Tenth Earl of Dundonald 1823 Jan. [?]
Cockroaches 1834 July 25
Coffin, James Henry 1857 Mar. 17; 1857 Apr. 1.
Coinage 1857 Mar. 11; 1857 Mar. 20.
Colden, Cadwallader David [?] 1825 Mar. 30; 1825 Apr. 4; 1825 Apr. 8; 1825 Aug. 1[?]; 1825[?]; 1830 July 13.
Collinson, Sir Richard 1851 Mar. 31
Compass 1848 Mar. 22
Compromise of 1850 1850 May 7
Concerts. District of Columbia. Washington, 1845[?] Jan. 30; 1845[?] Feb. 2; 1851 Mar. 21.
Concerts. Florida. Pensacola 1846 Sept. 9
Confederate States of America. Army, 1863 May 6; 1863 June 17; Printed Material: 1864 Sept. 20.
Confederate States of America. Army. Supplies and Stores 1863 Mar. 15
Confederate States of America. Army. Units. Army of Northern Virginia 1863[?] May 8; 1863[?] May 31; 1863[?] June 17; Printed Material: 1864 Sept. 20.
Confederate States of America. Navy, 1862 Oct. 27
Congressional Elections. 1853 1853 Aug. 14
Connecticut [?]. Description and Travel 1870 Dec. 16
Connecticut [?]. Iron Industry and Trade 1870 Dec. 16
Cooper, James Fenimore 1852 Mar. 1
Cooper, Thomas Abthorpe 1837 Dec. 31
Copper Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Charlotte 1853 Sept. 2
Copper Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Hipps[?] Mine 1849 Feb. 3; 1849 Feb. 13; 1849 Feb. 18; 1849 Feb. 28.
Copyright 1844 Apr. 18; 1844 May 5; 1844 May.
Corals 1850 Nov. 5
Corn Meal 1859 Sept. 11
Corn Planters (Machines) 1856 May 4
Corn Trade 1860 Jan. 2
Cotton Growing. Southern States 1849 May 16
Cotton Trade. North Carolina 1865 June 20; 1866 Dec. 6; 1866 Dec. 14.
Courts-Martial and Courts of Inquiry, 1825[?] Aug. 5; 1825[?] Aug. 19; 1830 Aug. 19; 1830 Aug. 25; 1842 Mar. 10; 1842 July 16; 1842 July 22; 1842 Sept. 24; 1843 Apr. 3; 1864 Feb. 29; Miscellany: 1864.
Couthuoy, John Pitty 1845[?] Jan. 30
Cox, Samuel Hanson [?] 1834 July 16
Craven, Thomas Tingey 1863 May 28; Legal Papers: 1865 Nov. 20.
Craven, Tunus Augustus MacDonough, 1863 Feb. 20
Crime and Criminals. China 1850 Oct. 2
Crime and Criminals. Hong Kong 1850 Oct. 31
Craige, Francis Burton 1858 Feb. 7
Craniology 1850 Nov. 25
Crittendon, John Jordan 1838 May 26
Croxall, Daniel C. 1830 Dec. 8; 1830 Dec. 25.
Crustacea 1850 Nov. 29; 1850 Dec. 31; 1851 Mar. 3.
Cullum, George Washington 1863 Feb. 28
Cuming, Hugh 1850, Nov. 29
Curacao. Description and Travel, 1848 May 31
Currency 1844 Dec. 31; 1874 Apr. 22.
Currency. North Carolina 1865 May 20; 1865 May 28.
Curtis, Edward (1801-1856) 1838 June 6
Curtis, Moses Ashley 1849 Apr.; 1849 May 21; 1849 June 9; 1849 Aug. 31; 1857 Sept. 5; 1857 Nov. 9; 1859 May 10; 1860 Jan. 3; 1871 Sept. 18.
Cutting, Francis Brockholst, 1854 Mar. 30; 1854 July 18.
Dahlgren, John Adolphus Bernard, 1863 Feb. 3; 1863 Feb. 12; 1863 Mar. 14; 1863 Mar. 18; 1863 Mar. 27; 1863 Apr. 1; 1863 June 9; 1863 June 17; 1870 July 15.
Dana, James Dwight (1813-1895), 1849 Aug. 14; 1857 Oct. 8; 1854 Dec. 20; 1857 Jan. 4; 1857 Jan. 31; 1857 Feb. 3; 1857 Apr. 14.
Dauphin and Susquehannah Coal Company, 1846 Jan. 14
Davis, Charles Henry (1807-1877), 1863 Mar. 16; 1870 Aug. 25.
Davis, Jefferson 1854 June 15
Davis, John Wesley 1844[?]; 1845 Feb. 9; 1849 Mar. 22.
Davis, Thomas Treadwell [?], Letter to: 1856 Apr. 21
Davis, Varina Anne (Howell), 1854 June 15
Day, Jeremiah B. [?] 1825 Aug. 13; 1825 Aug. 16.
Dayton, William Lewis Letter to: 1848 Dec. 16
Delaware River Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XV)
Dent, Edward John 1837 Jan. 30 (2)
Depressions. 1837 1837 Mar. 13
Depressions. 1857 1857 Oct. 1; 1857 Oct. 5; 1857 Oct. 11 (2); 1857 Oct. 13; 1857 Oct. 25; 1857 Nov. 1.
Depressions. 1857. Minnesota Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter V)
Depressions. 1867 1867 Feb. 20; 1867 Mar. 4.
Derby, Miller and Company 1849 Dec. 29
De Rosset, Moses John 1859 May 10
Dickerson, Mahlon Letter to: 1834 Dec. 13; Letter to: 1836 Oct. 13; Letter to: 1836 Nov. 3; Letter to: 1837 Jan. 30; Letter to: 1837 Dec. 7; 1836 May 13; 1837 Dec. 19; 1838 Jan. 8; 1838 Jan. 22; 1838 Feb. 5.
Dickerson, Mahlon [?] 1838 Jan. 6; 1838 Jan. 8.
Dickerson, Philemon 1836 May 22; 1836 May 23; 1836 May 28; 1836 June 4; 1836 June 10.
Dickinson, Daniel Stevens [?], 1851 Jan. 15
Dinners and Dining. District of Columbia. Washington 1828 Nov. 14
Dinners and Dining. Philippine Islands. Manila 1851 Jan. 27
Diseases. Care and Treatment 1834 July 25; 1850 July 24; 1862 Oct. 19.
Diseases. Cholera 1834 Aug. 24; 1834 Sept. 3; 1834 Sept. 9; 1834 Oct. 2; 1849 May 15; 1849 June 1; 1849 June 6; 1849 June 11; 1849 June 14; 1849 June 18; 1849 June 29.
Diseases. Cholera. District of Columbia. Washington 1849 July 4; 1849 July 9; 1849 July 11; 1849 Aug. 11; 1849 Aug. 14.
Diseases. Cholera. New York 1849 June 7
Diseases. Cholera. North Carolina 1849 May 8
Diseases. District of Columbia. Washington, 1848 Oct. 5; 1848 Oct. 9; 1849 Sept. 12.
Diseases. Dysentery 1850 July 24
Diseases. Epidemics. Cholera 1849 Jan. 3
Diseases. Epidemics. Yellow Fever 1849 Feb. 1; 1850 Mar. 14; 1850 Mar. 16.
Diseases. Influenza 1846 Aug. 29; 1846 Sept. 9.
Diseases. Malaria [?] 1848 Feb. 27
Diseases. Measles 1834 Apr. 23
Diseases. Measles. North Carolina 1857 Mar. 15
Diseases. North Carolina 1851 Jan. 2
Diseases. Scarlet Fever 1834 Apr. 23
Diseases. Smallpox 1850 Dec. 26
Diseases. Smallpox. Malta 1830 Sept. 18
Diseases. Smallpox. North Carolina 1851 Jan. 21
Diseases. Yellow Fever 1847 Oct. 26; 1850 Mar. 16; 1850 Mar. 17 (on letter of May 23).
Diseases. Yellow Fever. South Carolina. Charleston 1849 Oct. 12
District of Columbia. Balls (Parties), 1849 Mar. 18[?]
District of Columbia. Banks and Banking 1870 July 15
District of Columbia. Water Supply, 1860 Jan. 12
District of Columbia. Washington, 1863 Mar. 14; Legal Papers: Undated (2 Plates).
District of Columbia. Washington. Civil War 1862 Oct. 18; 1862 Oct. 23 (part of letter of Oct. 22); 1862 Nov.; 1863 Jan. 9; 1863 Mar. 15; 1863 Apr. 16; 1863 May 5; 1863 May 6; 1863 May 7; 1863 May 22; 1863 June 9; 1863 June 17 (2).
District of Columbia. Washington. Concerts 1845[?] Jan. 30; 1845[?] Feb. 2; 1851 Mar. 21.
District of Columbia. Washington. Description and Travel 1848 Nov. 30; 1849 Apr. 24.
District of Columbia. Washington. Dinners and Dining 1828 Nov. 14
District of Columbia. Washington. Diseases 1848 Oct. 5; 1848 Oct. 9; 1849 Sept. 12.
District of Columbia. Washington. Diseases. Cholera 1849 July 4; 1849 July 9; 1849 July 11; 1849 Aug. 11; 1849 Aug. 14.
District of Columbia. Washington. Economic Conditions 1867 Mar. 14
District of Columbia. Washington. Elections 1849 June 7
District of Columbia. Washington. Fires 1849 Nov. 15; 1853 May 31.
District of Columbia. Washington. Fourth of July Celebrations 1849 July 4
District of Columbia. Washington. Freedman's Bank 1870 July 15
District of Columbia. Washington. Gardeners 1849 June 11; 1849 June 22; 1849 Aug. 11; 1849 Aug. 14; 1849 Oct. 31.
District of Columbia. Washington. Georgetown. Gardens 1825 Aug. 19
District of Columbia. Washington. Greenhouses 1850 May 23; 1850 June 13; 1850 June; 1850 July 5; 1850 July 6; 1850 Aug. 5; 1850 Oct. 3; 1852 June 13; Financial Papers: 1850 June[?].
District of Columbia. Washington. Holmes Island Miscellany: Undated (2)
District of Columbia. Washington. Hotels 1871 Sept. 8
District of Columbia. Washington. Houses 1849 Nov. 21; 1849 Nov. 30; 1871 May 12.
District of Columbia. Washington. Land, 1874 June 9; 1874 June 10.
District of Columbia. Washington. Land Plats Broadside: 1874[?] May 12 (in Picture Cabinet III-3)
District of Columbia. Washington. National Institute Museum 1852 Sept. 17
District of Columbia. Washington. New Year 1863 Jan. 4
District of Columbia. Washington. Politics and Government 1874 May 1; 1874 June 23.
District of Columbia. Washington. Protestant Episcopal Church. St. John's Church 1825 Mar. 22
District of Columbia. Washington. Public Health 1825 Aug. 5
District of Columbia. Washington. Public Works 1848 Nov. 12; 1849 July 31; 1849 Aug. 10; 1849 Oct. 10; 1850 Feb. 1; 1851 May 7; 1851 May 8; 1851 May 25; 1870 June 3; 1870 July 15; 1870 Dec. 9; 1870 Dec. 21; 1871 Mar. 21; 1871 May 12; 1871 June 20; 1873 Jan. 25.
District of Columbia. Washington. Railroads 1871 Sept. 8; 1873 Nov. 3; 1873 Nov. 9.
District of Columbia. Washington. Secession 1862 Oct. 18; 1863 May 22.
District of Columbia. Washington. Slave Sales and Purchases 1854 Dec. 14
District of Columbia. Washington. Slaves. Hiring of 1852 Oct. 5; 1854 Dec. 14; 1854 Dec. 15.
District of Columbia. Washington. Social Life and Customs 1826 Jan. 26; 1845[?] Jan. 11; 1845[?] Jan. 30; 1845[?] Feb. 2; 1849 Dec. 8 (on letter of Dec. 5); 1852 May 3 (with letter of same date); 1863 Jan. 18; 1863 Feb. 6; 1863 Feb. 12; 1863 May 29.
District of Columbia. Washington. Washington Monument 1849 July 4
District of Columbia. Washington. Weddings 1836 July 2
District of Columbia. Washington. White House 1825[?] Apr. 9; 1828 Nov. 14.
District of Columbia. Washington. Women 1825[?] Apr. 9
Dix, John Adams 1862 Aug. 5
Dix, John Adams [?] 1849 May 15
Dixon, James [?] 1863 Jan. 9; 1863 Jan. 19; 1863 Jan. 23.
Dobbin, James Cochran 1853[?] Dec. 20
Dominican Republic. Description and Travel 1859 Aug. 16
Dougal, William H. 1849 Apr. 18; 1857 Apr. 14; 1857 Sept. 5; 1857 Sept. 12; 1857 Nov. 9.
Douglas, Stephen Arnold [?], 1854 Mar. 30
Downes, John (1784-1854) 1838 June 4; 1849 Dec. 26; 1850 Jan. 14; 1850 Jan. 21.
Drayton, William (1776-1846), 1830 June 20
Duels and Duelling 1827[?] Mar. 7
Duels and Duelling. Hawaii 1848 June 5
Du Pont, Samuel Francis 1862 Oct. 1; 1863 Apr. 3; 1863 Apr. 19; 1863 May 7 (part of letter of May 5).
Durham, Milton Jamison [?] 1874 May 18; 1874 May 28.
Duryée, Abram 1862 Dec. 3; 1862 Dec. 4.
Eames, Charles 1864 Feb. 29; Miscellany: 1864.
Earthquakes. Chile. Valparaiso 1823 Jan. [?]
Earthquakes. Peru. Lima 1823 Jan. [?]
Earthquakes. Philippine Islands. Manila, 1851 Jan. 27
Earthquakes. Venezuela. Caracas 1848 May 31
East India Marine Society 1836 Nov. 3
Eclipses. Solar 1834 Dec. 13
Ecuador. Quayaquil. Social Life and Customs 1822 Aug. 14
Edmunds, George Franklin 1874 May 18
Eimeo. Description and Travel, 1839 Sept. 26
Ellet, Charles Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XIV, pp. 150-151)
Ellis, John Willis Letter to: 1859 Mar. 23; 1859 Apr. 10; 1859 May 10; 1859 July 3; 1859 July 10; 1859 July 20; 1860 Oct. 9.
Ellsworth, Henry Leavitt 1844 Dec. 31
England. Liverpool. Description and Travel 1836 Aug. 28
England. London. London Exhibition, 1851 1851 June 11
English Abroad. Australia 1839 Dec. 3
English Abroad. Brazil 1838 Dec. 18
English Abroad. France 1830 Dec. 21; 1830 Dec. 25.
English Abroad. Hong Kong 1850 Oct. 31; 1850 Dec. 3; 1851 July 9.
English Abroad. Italy 1830 Nov. 5
English Abroad. Macao 1850 July 24; 1850 Sept. 2.
English Abroad. Tunis 1830 Sept. 18
Ericsson, John 1836 Oct. 28
Europe. Politics and Government, 1850 July 1
Eustis, Henry Lawrence 1850 Oct. 2; 1850 Oct. 22; 1850 Nov. 7; 1850 Nov. 10; 1850 Dec. 3; 1850 Dec. 22.
Evans, Clement Anselm [?] 1863 May 6
Everett, Alexander Hill 1850 June 23
Everett, Edward 1852 Nov. 1; 1855 Dec. 17.
Eubank, Thomas 1849 Apr. 28; 1849 May 6; 1849 May 14; 1849 July 31; 1849 Aug. 14; 1849 Aug. 15; 1849 Aug. 27.
Ewing, Thomas (1829-1896) [?], 1849 Apr. 27; 1849 Aug. 10; 1849 Aug. 11; 1849 Aug. 27; 1849 Oct. 31.
Excelsior Railroad 1853 Jan. 3
Exploration of the Pacific 1855 Feb. 3
Farms. Delaware Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XV)
Farragut, David Glasgow 1863 Apr. 3; 1863 Apr. 16; 1863 June 9.
Farrelly, John Wilson 1849 Apr. 28
Fasts and Feasts 1863 May 5
Fiji Islands 1840 Aug. 10; 1849 Nov. 15; Volume: 1840 July 15.
Fiji Islands. Cannibalism 1840 Aug. 10
Fiji Islands. Discovery and Exploration 1840 June 22
Fiji Islands. Missionaries 1840 Aug. 10
Fiji Islands. Murder 1849 Aug. 10; Volume: 1840 July 15.
Fiji Islands. Native Races 1840 Aug. 10; 1840 Aug. 18.
Fillmore, Abigail (Powers) 1852 Dec. 8
Fillmore, Mary Abigail 1852 Dec. 8
Fillmore, Millard 1850 July 12; 1852 July 21; 1856 July 24.
Fire Alarms. Massachusetts. Boston 1852 Nov. [?]; 1852 Dec. 3.
Fire Departments. New York. New York, Writings: "Fire Department"
Fires. China. Canton 1851 Oct. 9[?]
Fires. North Carolina. Charlotte 1871 Nov. 17
Fires. District of Columbia. Washington, 1849 Nov. 15; 1853 May 31.
First National Bank of Charlotte, 1865 June 20; 1866 Dec. 14; 1867 Feb. 10; 1867 Apr. 4; 1867 May 22; 1867 May 28; 1867 June 28; 1867 Aug. 25; 1867 Sept. 9; 1867 Sept. 11; 1867 Sept. 30; 1867 Dec. 16; 1867 Dec. 18; 1867 Dec. 22; 1867 Dec.; 1868 Feb. 3.
Fish, Hamilton 1843 Nov. 16; 1843 Dec. 1; 1844 Dec. 27; 1852 July 24.
Fish, Hamilton [?] 1846 Dec. 31
Fish, Mrs. Hamilton 1843 Dec. 2
Fish 1849 Apr. 6; 1850 July 10; 1850 Aug. 7; 1857 Jan. 4.
Fisher, Charles Frederick Letter to: 1860 June 25; 1858 Feb. 7; 1858 Mar. 5; 1858 July 11; 1858 Oct. 24; 1858 Dec. 12; 1859 Jan. 25; 1859 Feb. 7; 1859 Feb. 20; 1859 Mar. 23; 1859 Apr. 10; 1859 Apr. 23; 1859 May 10; 1859 June 29; 1859 July 3; 1859 July 10; 1859 July 20; 1859 July 2
Florida. Economic Conditions, 1832 Feb. 27
Florida. Immigration 1832 Feb. 27
Florida. Indians 1849 Sept. 30
Florida. Pensacola. Concerts, 1846 Sept. 9
Florida. Pensacola. Women 1846 Jan. 7
Florida. St. Joseph. Harbors, 1836 May 1
Flour. Manufacture and Trade 1859 Apr. 23
Flour. Manufacture and Trade. North Carolina 1857 July 5; 1858 May 9; 1858 June 24; 1858 June 25.
Flour Mills. North Carolina 1850 Apr. 13; 1856 Aug. 26; 1857 Feb.-June (scattered); 1857 July 12; 1857 Aug. 2; 1858 Aug. 8-1859 Sept. 11 (scattered); 1859 Sept. 11.
Flügel, Johann Gottfried [?], Letter to: 1849 Dec. 22 (enclosed with letter of 1850 Mar. 14)
Folsom, George 1874 Dec. 28
Foote, Andrew Hull 1862 Oct. 18; 1863 Mar. 27; 1863 Apr. 2.
Foote, Henry Stuart 1852 May 3 (with letter of same date)
Forbes, Robert Bennet 1850 Sept. 2; 1859 June 16.
Force, Peter 1874 Dec. 28
Formosa. Coal 1851 Mar. 31
Formosa. Foreign Relations. United States 1851 July 20
Forrest, French 1848 June 30; 1850 Apr. 26.
Forsyth, John (1780-1841) 1825 Aug. 16
Fort Darling. Virginia. Fortifications, Miscellany: 1862 Aug. 25
Fort McAllister. South Carolina, 1863 Feb. 22
Fort Monroe. Virginia 1862 Aug. 21 (enclosed with letter of Aug. 22)
Fort Snelling. Minnesota Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter VI)
Foster, John Gray 1863 Feb. 8; 1863 Feb. 18; Printed Material: 1864 Sept. 20.
Foster, Lafayette Sabine 1863 Feb. 3
Foundries. Ohio. Bellaire 1855[?]
Fourth of July Celebrations. District of Columbia. Washington 1849 July 4
Fourth of July Celebrations. New York, 1830 July
Fox, Gustavus Vasa 1863 Apr. 4; 1863 Apr. 19; 1863 June 9.
France. Americans in 1830 Dec. 21
France. Army 1830[?] Sept. 3
France. Ballet 1836 Oct. 9
France. Balls (Parties) 1831 Jan. 13
France. Description and Travel, 1830 Dec. 21
France. Diplomatic Consular Service, 1830 Sept. 12; 1830 Sept. 18; 1870 July 15.
France. English in 1830 Dec. 21; 1830 Dec. 25.
France. Foreign Relations. Hawaii, 1851 Mar. 28
France. Marseilles. Description and Travel 1830 Dec. 8; 1830 Dec. 25; 1831 Jan. 2.
France. National Guard 1831 Jan. 2
France. Navy 1830[?] Sept. 3; 1830 Dec. 21.
France. Nîmes 1831 Jan. 11
France. Opera 1836 Oct. 9
France. Paris. Clothing and Dress, 1836 Nov. 7
France. Roads 1830 Dec. 21
France. Social Life and Customs, 1830 Dec. 25
France. St. Germain. Social Life and Customs 1836 Oct. 9
France. Stagecoaches 1830 Dec. 21
France. Toulon. Description and Travel, 1830 Dec. 21
Franco-German War, 1870-1871, 1870 July 15; 1870 Aug. 25.
Franklin, Jane (Griffin), Lady, 1849 June 24; 1849 June 26.
Franklin, Sir John 1849 May 20; 1849 May 21; 1849 May 28; 1849 May 30; 1849 June 8; 1849 June 13; 1849 June 24; 1849 June 26; 1849 June 30; 1850 Dec. 3; 1851 Mar. 31; 1852 Mar. 1; 1852 Mar. 18; Clipping: 1863 Feb. 9 (attached to letter of 1862 Aug. 6).
Franklin, William Buel 1863 Jan. 27; 1863 Jan. 28.
Freedman's Bank. District of Columbia. Washington 1870 July 15
Freedmen 1853 June 20
Frémont, John Charles (1813-1890), 1848 Oct. 10; 1862 Sept. 24.
French Abroad. Algeria 1830 Oct. 4
Frye, William Pierce [?] 1874 Jan. 24; 1874 May 18; 1874 May 28.